(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
いくよ！
Here we go!
どーまいべすと！
作詞・作曲：キノシタ
Do My Best!
Lyrics/Composition: Kinoshita
ハチャメチャカラフルデイズ
Hectic, colorful days
攻略法を探してる
Looking for a strategy
リセットボタンなんてあるわけないし
There's no such thing as a reset button
縛りプレイもいいとこじゃない
Isn't this a bit of a challenge run?
そんなの分かりきってる
I know that all too well
それなら思い出して
In that case, remember
夢を奏でるあの星のこと
About that star playing out our dreams
最初はダメダメでもいいからさ
It's okay to be a mess at first
ほらリズムに合わせて
Come on, match the rhythm
ワン・ツー・エン・チャイ！
One, two, and try!
予測不可能なんだ 本当のところは
It's unpredictable, to tell the truth
次のページのことだよ
The next page, that is
（あい！たん！たん！）
(Ai! Tan! Tan!)
怖いことなんてないよ
There's nothing to be afraid of
その続きにせーので飛び込んじゃおう
Let's dive into the rest of it on three
（じゅー！しー！いー！）
(Ju! Shi! I!)
だからドゥー・マイ・ベスト！ ドゥー・マイ・ベスト！
So, do my best! Do my best!
テンションは弾けて空にポジティブ
Tension bursts, positive in the sky
おててアテンションプリーズ テンションもブンブンで
Attention please, with tension booming
ドキドキのボリューム最大で行こうよ
Let's crank up the excitement to the max
泣いちゃって笑っちゃってもいいでしょ
It's fine to cry or laugh, right?
甘酸っぱいスパイス この今をめいっぱいさ
Bittersweet spice, let's live this moment to the fullest
楽しんでいこうよ
And have some fun!
まだまだまだまだ止まれない
We still can't stop, not yet
そんな世界が大好きだよ
I love a world like that
声に出して ドゥー・マイ・ベスト！
Sing it out! Do my best!
チンプンカンプンカラフルデイズ
Incomprehensible, colorful days
冒険の書はどこにもない
There's no record of our adventure anywhere
セーブポイント やり直しの毎日じゃ
If every day was just save points and restarts
ワクワクの音色も奏でられない
We couldn't play the melody of excitement
そんなのつまんないでしょ
That would be boring, wouldn't it?
それなら耳を澄まして
In that case, listen closely
大好きな音が聞こえてくるよ
You'll hear the sounds you love
明日は明日の風が吹くからさ
Because tomorrow is a brand new day
ほらリズムに合わせて ワン・ツー・エン・チャイ！
Come on, match the rhythm! One, two, and try!
ヤバみになっちゃおーな 本当のところは
Let's go crazy! To tell the truth
次のページのことだよ
It's all about the next page
（あい！たん！たん！）
(Ai! Tan! Tan!)
溢れるリズム繋いで
Connecting the overflowing rhythms
君だけの気持ちを今描きちゃおう
Let's paint your unique feelings right now
（じゅー！しー！いー！）
(Ju! Shi! I!)
だからドゥー・マイ・ベスト！
So, do my best!
ぐるぐるきらり 100文字のテンション プリアテンション プリ
Spinning and shining, 100-character tension, please attention, please
キラキラのぼり Volume Max でいこう！
Sparklingly rising, let's go at Max Volume!
単純で限界ないエモーション あたふたしてる
Simple and boundless emotion, being flustered
これからも目一杯さ
From now on too, to the very fullest
仲良くよろしくね！
Let's get along well!
まだまだ まだ
More and more, still more
あとどれくらい
How much longer?
そんな明日を
Towards that tomorrow
目指していこう
Let's keep aiming
もう一歩 Do my best!
One more step, do my best!
お星様に
To the stars
お願い事
I make a wish
早く隣に並べますように
I hope I can stand beside you soon
冷めないように
So it doesn't cool down
魔法をかけて
I'll cast a spell
ワクワクがバクバクしちゃいそう！
My excitement feels like it's going to burst!
みんなー！騒げーーー！
Everyone! Make some noise!
今気付いちゃったんだ 本当のところは
I just realized it now, to tell the truth
次のページのことだよ I can be...
It's about the next page, I can be...
楽しみすぎるから さっとこの続きに
Because I'm looking forward to it so much, straight to the sequel
せーので飛び込んじゃおう！
Let's dive in together!
だから Do my best, Do my best テンションはじけて
So Do my best, Do my best, tension bursting
きらりこっち向いて プリ アテンション プリ
Sparklingly look this way, please attention, please
ドキドキのぼり Volume Max でいこう！
Heart pounding and rising, let's go at Max Volume!
泣いちゃって笑っちゃって エモーション あたふたして
Crying and laughing, emotion, being flustered
この今を目一杯さ 楽しんでいこうよ！
Let's enjoy this moment to the very fullest!
まだまだ まだ止まれない そんな世界に大好き宣言
I still can't stop yet, a declaration of love to such a world
声に出して Do my best!
Say it out loud, do my best!
合言葉は…
The keyword is...
Do my best!
大空スバル4周年！4th Anniversary Live 始まるよ！
Oozora Subaru 4th Anniversary! The 4th Anniversary Live is starting!
盛り上がっていくぞーーー！！
Let's get fired up!!
君は聞こえる? 僕のこの声が
Can you hear it? This voice of mine
闇に虚しく 吸い込まれた
Was swallowed up in vain into the darkness
もしも世界が 意味を持つなら
If the world had a meaning
こんな気持ちも 無駄ではない
Then even these feelings wouldn't be in vain
憧れに押しつぶされて あきらめてたんだ
I was crushed by my longings and had given up
果てしない空の色も 知らないで
Without even knowing the color of the endless sky
走り出した想いが今でも
The feelings that started to run, even now
この胸を確かに 叩いているから
Are certainly beating within my chest
今日の僕が その先に続く
The me of today will go on beyond that
僕らなりの明日を 築いていく
And build a tomorrow that's uniquely ours
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer is, yes, it's always right here
過ぎた季節を 嘆く暇はない
There's no time to grieve for the seasons gone by
二度と迷って しまわぬように
So that I never get lost again
数え切れない ほんの些細な
Countless, truly trivial...
そんな後悔 抱えたまま
...regrets like those, while clutching them
その背中だけ追いかけて ここまで来たんだ
I've come this far just chasing after that back
探していた 僕だけにできること
Searching for what only I can do
あの日くれた 言葉が今でも
The words you gave me that day, even now
この胸に確かに 届いているから
Are certainly reaching into my chest
昨日よりも 今日僕は僕の
Even more than yesterday, today I...
生まれてきた理由に 気付いていく
...am realizing the reason I was born
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer is, yes, it's always right here
すべてがまるで当たり前みたいだった
Everything seemed so natural
当たり前みたいだった
It seemed so natural
遠い日々はまだ終わらない
The distant days aren't over yet
そしてまた
And again
走り出した想いが今でも
The feelings that started running even now
この胸を確かに叩いてるから
Are surely beating in this heart
今日の僕がその先に続く
The me of today continues beyond that
僕らなりの明日を築いていく
Building our own tomorrow
答えはそういつもここにある
The answer, yes, is always here
サマーハイヒール
Summer High Heel
グラスの氷 カラカラ かき回して ほら
Stirring the ice in the glass, clatter clatter, look
なんかいい感じでしょう
It's a nice feeling, isn't it?
ねえ ちょっと足も組んでみて そっと遠くを見つめ
Hey, try crossing your legs a bit, gazing quietly into the distance
なんかそれっぽい feeling
A feeling like that
大人ぶった summer time だけど 私には全然物足りない
An adult-like summer time, but for me, it's not enough at all
裸足になって海へ行きたい すぐに
I want to go to the sea barefoot, right now
水着に着替え go dive! 水しぶき じゃ足りない
Change into a swimsuit and go dive! A splash isn't enough
濡れた髪 結んで 大胆な lady
Tying up wet hair, a bold lady
ギラギラ 焼け Sunshine
Glaringly burning Sunshine
小麦肌 憧れて 私らしく 夏を
Longing for tanned skin, in my own way, the summer
メイクしちゃうからね!
I'll make it happen!
熱くなりすぎた身体 クリームソーダで
My body's gotten too hot, with a cream soda
cool down
こだわりフレーム サングラスかけ パラソルの下で
Wearing stylish frames and sunglasses, under the parasol
優雅なスタイル 決まってる
Looking elegant
砂浜を舞うビーチボール 不意に頭を過る君の姿
A beach ball dancing on the sand, suddenly your image crosses my mind
来年こそは二人きりで
Next year, for sure, just the two of us
過ごせたら
If we could spend it...
火照り出す身体
The body starting to flush
潮風浴びて
Basking in the sea breeze
イヤフォン越しのサマーチューン
A summer tune through earphones
上がる体温
Rising body temperature
今気分は最高!
The mood right now is the best!
だからもうダメ!
So I can't take it anymore!
水着に着替え go dive! 全身で海感じたい
Change into a swimsuit and go dive! I want to feel the sea with my whole body
脇目も振らないで はじけちゃって
Without looking aside, just let loose
キラキラ 眩い sunrise これぞ夏の真髄
Sparkling, dazzling sunrise, this is the essence of summer
大人に憧れた日々 もう少し子供のままで
The days I longed to be an adult, stay a child a little longer
私らしく夏を
In my own way, the summer
メイクしちゃおう!
Let's make it happen!
始まるでがんす！
It's starting, de-kansu!
あいまい３センチ そりゃぷにってことかい？ ちょっ！
Vague three centimeters, does that mean it's squishy? Wait!
らっぴんぐが制服…だふってことない？ ぷっ！
Wrapping in a uniform... it's not like it's baggy, is it? Pfft!
がんばっちゃ やっっちゃっちゃ そんときゃーっちゃーりびっず ごー
Let's work hard, do it do it, then catch it, let's go
あっせふっ あっせふっ どんにまにだにだにふりー
Sweat it out, sweat it out, whatever happens, it's free
もってけ！セーラーふく
作詞：畑 亜貴 作曲：神前 暁
Motteke! Sailor Fuku
Lyrics: Aki Hata, Composition: Satoru Kosaki
なんかだる なんかだる 愛してる あれ一個が違ってるんるー
Feeling a bit lazy, feeling a bit lazy, I love you, wait, one's different!
なやみん棒 鉄棒 おいしん棒 いい加減にしなさい
Worrying stick, iron bar, gourmet stick, give it a rest!
飛んでったアイツの火照るカラダって いわゆるふつーの女の子
His body flew away flushed, just your typical girl
驚いたあたしだけ？ 豚骨（とんこつ）ハリガネおかわりだだだだだ
Was I the only one surprised? Another serving of tonkotsu harigane noodles!
BON-BON おーえん団
BON-BON cheering squad
Let's Get! チェリーパイ
Let's get! Cherry pie
RAN-RAN かんげい会
RAN-RAN welcoming party
Look Up! せんせーしょん
Look up! Sensation
はい！ 存在感てんてんてん 小惑星
Yes! Presence dot dot dot, asteroid
ぶつかって溶けました ぼーぜん想い出はシレンジャー
It collided and melted, blank memories are a challenge
もっていけ！ 最後に笑っちゃうのはあたしのはず
Take it away! The one laughing at the end should be me
セーラーふくだからです 結論！
Because it's a sailor uniform, conclusion!
月曜日なのに機嫌悪いの どうするよ？
It's Monday, so why are you in a bad mood? What'll you do?
夏服がいいのです キャワイイ
I like summer uniforms, they're cute!
制服３センチ そりゃちゅーちょだや！
Uniform three centimeters, that's hesitation!
がんばって Yeah! 待ってて Yeah!
Good luck, Yeah! Wait for it, Yeah!
どんにまにだにだにふりー
Whatever happens, it's free
もにゃりんぼー 下がり 恋したり まだ内緒にしといて凛々
Feeling a bit fuzzy, down, falling in love, keep it a secret for now, dignified
甘えん坊 用心棒 通信簿 ちょうだいって玉砕
Spoiled child, bodyguard, report card, give it to me, a complete defeat
踏んでったアイツに小指痛いって 大げさチラリ黒ニーハイ
He stepped on my toe and it hurts, an exaggerated glimpse of black knee-highs
絶対領域ちゃん 生足ツルピカおねだりだだだだだ
Absolute territory-chan, smooth bare legs, I'm begging you!
BON-BON ごちそーさま
BON-BON thanks for the meal
Get Up! パーティーで
Get up! At the party
YAI-YAI そらんぶし
YAI-YAI Soran-bushi
What's Up? せんせーしょん
What's up? Sensation
おい！ 喪失感てんてんてん アルバイト
Hey! Feeling of loss dot dot dot, part-time job
探したら見つかって 当然人生まると決めなす
I searched and found it, naturally decided my life is a circle
やってみな！ 真剣に狙っちゃうのはあたしの挑戦
Give it a try! Taking a serious shot is my challenge
セーラーふく着替えても あたし
Even if I change out of my sailor uniform, I'm still me
週末はどうよ？ ちら見せなんてありきたり
How's the weekend? Showing a little is so ordinary
制服は簡単よ 楽ちん
Uniforms are easy, comfortable
風さん覚め 抱きついてガマンだ ぎゅっ
The wind wakes up, bear it by hugging tight!
おめでとう Yeah! 好きだよ Yeah!
Congratulations, Yeah! I love you, Yeah!
あいしゅうがしゅうがすうぃー
Melancholy is sweet
BON-BON もっぺんおーえん団
BON-BON cheering squad one more time
U-U-A-A-!
RAN-RAN ちょっちょっ期
RAN-RAN short-short term
FU-FU-O-O-!
はい！ エデュケーション ラッキー ABC
Yes! Education, lucky ABC
おんたかだおんたかだ おにゃおにゃ晴れてほれっぴひれんだ
Ontakada ontakada, it's cleared up, look at that!
もっていけ！ 最後に笑っちゃうのはあたしのはず
Take it away! The one laughing at the end should be me
セーラーふくだからです 結論！
Because it's a sailor uniform, conclusion!
月曜日なのに機嫌悪いの どうするよ？
It's Monday, so why are you in a bad mood? What'll you do?
夏服がいいのです キャワイイ
I like summer uniforms, they're cute!
やっぱりね 最後に笑っちゃうのはあたしのはず
Just as I thought, the one laughing at the end should be me
セーラーふくだからです 結論！
Because it's a sailor uniform, conclusion!
でも焼いてもよし！
But baking it is fine too!
あいまい３センチ そりゃぷにってことかい？ わぉ！
Vague three centimeters, does that mean it's squishy? Wow!
らっぴんぐが制服 よしふりってことない？ ぼー！
Wrapping in a uniform, does that mean it's swinging? Bo!
がんばっちゃ やっっちゃっちゃ あときゃーっちゃーりびっず はー
Let's work hard, do it do it, later catch it, haa
あっせふっ あっせふっ どんにまにだにだにびゅーず
Sweat it out, sweat it out, whatever happens, it's views
つっ、つかれたにょ…
I-I'm tired-nyo...
大丈夫！？
Are you okay!?
やばすぎあにゃ！
This is too crazy!
おまえ元気だなー！
You're so energetic!
あのダンス踊ったあと！
After dancing like that!
めちゃめちゃきつかったよ今のダンス！
That dance was super tough just now!
あああ、死ぬにょ…
Aaa, I'm dying-nyo...
よかったよ！
It was great!
もってけ！セーラーふくでした！
That was 'Motteke! Sailor Fuku'!
はいということでね、皆さんどうですか？このポンポンダンスね！
Okay, so everyone, how do you like this pom-pom dance?
可愛い！
So cute!
これ！
Look at this!
可愛いでしょう、これ！これはですね、ちょっとポンポンをね、作ってみました。
It's cute, right? For this, we tried making some pom-poms.
せっかくなんでね、写真とか撮りますか？
Since we're here, should we take some photos?
おおー！
Oh!
いいんじゃないですか？
Sounds good, doesn't it?
撮りたい撮りたい！集合集合！結構ね、大きいからね。
I want to, I want to! Group photo! They're pretty big.
じゃ、ちょっと身長高いから後ろ…ほら、ぼたん真ん中行きなさい、早く！
Since you're tall, go to the back... Look, Botan, go to the middle, hurry!
なんなんだお前は！
What's with you?!
何ポジションだ！
What position is this!
じゃあしゃがむか。
Okay, I'll crouch.
チョコ先生、後ろ…膝ついて。
Choco-sensei, behind... get on your knees.
なんか、なんだっけ？
Wait, what was it?
こうする？
Like this?
可愛い！
Cute!
もうちょいぼたんちゃん、左がいいかな？
Maybe a little more to the left, Botan-chan?
こっち？
This way?
あ、いい！
Ah, nice!
チョコ先生も一歩内側がいいかな？
Choco-sensei, maybe one step inward too?
これぐらい？
About here?
あ、いいですね！
Ah, looks good!
いいですねー！
Looks good!
シャンシャンシャンシャン！
Snap snap snap snap!
顔隠れる、顔隠れる。
Our faces are being covered.
はいチーズ！
Say cheese!
シャンシャンシャンシャン！
Snap snap snap snap!
シャッター押してください！
Please press the shutter!
お願いします！
Please!
お願いしまーす！
Pleeease!
はい！ということでね、
Alright! So,
せっかくなんでね、1人ずつも撮ってみますか！
since we're here, should we take individual shots too?
おおー！
Oh!
やりたーい！
I want to!
最初誰から？
Who's first?
ぼたんちゃん？
Botan-chan?
私？
Me?
あ、お、じゃあちょっとみんな、とびきり激写頼む。
Oh, okay. Everyone, take some great shots for me.
いいね！
Nice!
めちゃめちゃ映り込んどるやないかい！
You're totally in the shot!
お前元気だなマジで！
You're so energetic, seriously!
ずたっ！
Zuta!
どんなんがいいかな？
What kind of pose should I do?
可愛い！
Cute!
胸の前で持つのも可愛いよ。
Holding them in front of your chest is cute too.
あ、こう？
Ah, like this?
こう？
Like this?
可愛い！
Cute!
シャンシャン…
Snap...
なんでその顔なんだよ！
Why that face?!
いいですね！
Looks good!
続いて、ルーナ！
Next, Luna!
はい！
Yes!
んーなななななななー！
Nnananananana!
なんなんそれ！
What is that?!
出てきた！
She came out!
なんか出てきた！
Something came out!
んなんなんな！
Nna nna nna!
可愛い！
Cute!
あ、可愛い！
Ah, cute!
いいわよいいわよ！
Good, good!
はい、スバル行ってきなさい！
Okay, Subaru, go on!
早く！
Hurry!
しゅしゅしゅしゅ！
Shu shu shu shu!
お前めっちゃ元気だなマジで！
You're so energetic, seriously!
はい！ということでね、
Alright! So,
本日の主役、こんにちは！大空スバルです！
today's protagonist... Hello! I'm Oozora Subaru!
似合うねー！
It suits you!
黄色似合うね！
Yellow suits you!
めちゃめちゃ似合ってる！
It really suits you!
本当？
Really?
似合ってるわ！
It suits me!
はい！ということでね、
Alright! So,
ありがとうございます！
thank you very much!
可愛い！
Cute!
いいなーなねー！
How nice!
じゃあチョコ先生！
Okay, Choco-sensei!
はい！
Yes!
ホーーーイ！
Hoo-ey!
似合うね！
It suits you!
いいね！
Nice!
可愛い！
Cute!
ちょっとセクシーだな！
A bit sexy!
やっぱデモセクシーだな。
It's definitely sexy.
なんか胸のほうが目立ってね？
The chest stands out more, doesn't it?
確かに！
For sure!
はち切れんじゃねえよ！
Don't let it burst!
しょうがないじゃない！
I can't help it!
しょうがなくねえよ！
Yes you can!
はい！ということでね、
Alright! So,
はい集合！
okay, everyone gather!
はい、チョコ先生もポンポン置いてきて。
Okay, Choco-sensei, put your pom-poms away too.
はい！ということでですね、
Alright! So,
ここまでね、ライブをやってきて、
we've been doing the live performance up to this point,
初MCなんですけれども。
and this is our first MC segment.
ちょっとどうだった、スバルのライブはさ？
So, how was Subaru's live performance?
めっちゃ可愛かった！
It was so cute!
でもバトン凄くなかった？
But wasn't the baton part amazing?
バトン凄かった！
It was!
ちょっとね、まあ練習しました！
I did... well, practice a bit!
ご飯食べに行った時さ、遅れてきてさ、
When we went out to eat, she came late,
ごめん遅れたってバトンめっちゃ持っててさ。
and was like "Sorry I'm late" while holding a baton.
嘘でしょ！
No way!
マジで！？
Seriously!?
マジマジ！
Really, really!
天ぷら屋、天ぷら屋！
At the tempura shop!
お前待たせて！
Keeping us waiting!
ご飯揚げててさ、なんで棒持ってるの？
While the food was frying, we were like "Why are you holding a stick?"
とか言ってたら、今日の布石だったんだな。
but it was setup for today.
結構ね、前からね、
I've been practicing for
練習してたりとかしてました！はい！
quite a while! Yes!
そしてですね、
And also,
ちょっとこの後ね、新衣装があるんですよ！
there's a new costume after this!
なんだって！？
What?!
Really?!
段取りのようなリアクション助かる！
Helpful reaction just like a rehearsal!
1種類かい！？
Is it just one type?!
言っちゃったね、それは！
You said it!
ちょっとね、まあまあまあ！
Well, well, well!
なんて言ったよ、この！
What did you say?!
1種類！
Just one!
そうなのなの？
Is that so?
本当？
Really?
おおー！
Oh!
ちょっと！言えない言えない！
Wait! I can't say, I can't say!
これはちょっと見ないと！
You have to see it!
でもね、もう腰抜かしちゃってよ、
But really, it'll make you lose your legs,
スバルマジで！自分でもね！
Subaru seriously! Even for me!
はい！ということで、
Alright! So,
今年4周年ですからね、スバルね！
it's the 4th anniversary this year for Subaru!
そうですよ！
That's right!
4周年おめでとう！
Happy 4th Anniversary!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ルーナ待って体力ついたね！
Luna, wait, you've gained stamina!
本当？
Really?
全然息切れしてない、本当だよ！
She's not out of breath at all! It's true!
めちゃめちゃ元気！
So energetic!
凄いよ、筋トレってこんなに凄いんだ、
Amazing, muscle training is so incredible.
すげえ！
Wow!
凄いなー！
Impressive!
はい！ということでですね、
Alright! So,
ちょっとこの後まだまだ続くのでね、
there's still more to come after this,
よかったら皆さん是非応援してください！
so everyone please cheer us on!
はーい！
Okay!
頑張れ！
Good luck!
頑張れー！
よし！それじゃあ、
Alright! Well then,
スバルもね、今も頑張るから、
I'll keep doing my best too,
みんな本当にありがとね！
so thank you everyone, really!
頑張って！
Do your best!
ありがとね！
Thank you!
頑張れ！
Good luck!
またねー！
See ya!
はい！ということでですね、
Alright! So,
それではですね…
well then...
やばい、1人になっちゃった。
Oh no, I'm all alone.
こっからもですね、まだまだみんなが驚くようなことが
From here on too, many things that will
いっぱいあると思うので、楽しみにしていてください！
surprise everyone, so please look forward to it!
はい！
Alright!
それではですね、次の曲に行きたいと思います！
Well then, I'd like to move on to the next song!
何が始まるかは、
What will start...
曲始まってからの、曲始まってからのお楽しみです！
you'll have to wait until the song starts to find out!
それではですね、
Well then,
いきますよ！
here we go!
はい！ということでですね、それではですね…
Alright! So, well then...
やばい、1人になっちゃった。
Oh no, I'm all alone.
こっからもですね、まだまだみんなが驚くようなことが
From here on too, many things that will
いっぱいあると思うので、楽しみにしていてください！
surprise everyone, so please look forward to it!
はい！
Alright!
それではですね、次の曲に行きたいと思います！
Well then, I'd like to move on to the next song!
何が始まるかは、
What will start...
曲始まってからの、曲始まってからのお楽しみです！
you'll have to wait until the song starts to find out!
それではですね、いきますよ！
Well then, here we go!
シュシュ
Shu shu
それでは聞いてください
Now, please listen.
4周年特別メドレー Shiny Smily Story
4th Anniversary Special Medley: Shiny Smily Story
手に入れたい それぞれ...
I want to get it, with each...
...違った 心で
...different heart.
走れ今
Run now.
4周年特別メドレー 太陽少女
4th Anniversary Special Medley: Taiyou Shoujo
ギラギラの太陽が ワクワクが待ちきれない
The glittering sun, I can't wait for the excitement.
あれもしたい これもしたい レッツサマータイム
I want to do that, I want to do this, let's summertime!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
青い空と 白い雲が
The blue sky and white clouds...
心のボルテージ 上げてゆく
...raise my heart's voltage.
ラムネ色の Ｔシャツをね
A ramune-colored T-shirt...
今年一番の レコメンド
...is my top recommendation this year.
走り出した 海岸線
Starting to run along the coastline,
どこまでも 行けそうだね
it looks like we can go anywhere.
数えきれない 夏休みチャレンジ
Countless summer vacation challenges,
君も一緒に行こう
you come along too.
あっと言う間に 進んでく時計
The clock moves in the blink of an eye,
短すぎちゃうね マイサマータイム
it's too short, my summertime.
全部最高の メモリアルにしたい
I want to make it all the best memorial,
追い風 みんな連れていけ
tailwind, take everyone with you.
スバラシイ太陽が サンサンせーのでジャンプ
The wonderful sun is shining, jump on three!
はじける汗 宝石みたいに
Bursting sweat, like jewels,
キラキラ眩しく 輝け
shining brightly, glitter.
ギラギラの太陽が ドキドキがいっぱいです
The glittering sun, I'm full of excitement.
あれもしよう これもやろう レッツサマータイム
Let's do that, let's do this, let's summertime!
4周年特別メドレー ぷ・れ・あ・で・す！
4th Anniversary Special Medley: Plave
ちょこっとやんちゃで ニコッと元気な
A little mischievous and smiling with energy,
キラッとスマイル アイドル
a glittering smile idol.
毎日をもっと 楽しくしたい
I want to make every day more fun,
貪欲に ウィズアドベンチャー
greedily, with adventure!
ひらひらスカートも ちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
I can even wear a fluttering skirt properly.
だからもっと お気に入りになってもいいよ
So it's okay to become even more of a favorite,
一緒に 大空に飛び立とう
together, let's fly into the big sky!
光れスターライト どんな輝きの中も
Shine starlight, in any kind of radiance,
強いきらめき 君に届いているかな
a strong sparkle, I wonder if it's reaching you.
１ミリでも 伝わればいい
If even one millimeter gets across, it's fine.
チャージ チャレンジ 全力アクセル
Charge, challenge, full throttle!
頑張る君へ 一番乗りのスマイルを
To you who are doing your best, the first smile
送るスバルちゃんねる エブリデイ
from Subaru Channel, sent every day.
悩んでないで みんなで
Don't worry, everyone together!
4周年特別メドレー Shiny Smily Story
4th Anniversary Special Medley: Shiny Smily Story
憧れの舞台 立ちたい
The stage of my dreams, I want to stand on it.
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine like myself.
時に涙して また笑い合いたい
Sometimes shedding tears, wanting to laugh together again.
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢手に入れたい
I want to get that dream.
踏み出そう 奇跡の一歩を
Let's take a step, a step of miracles.
生き切らせて 夢追いかけたい
Let me live it out, I want to chase my dreams.
ワクワク止まらない 想像を超えてゆく
The excitement doesn't stop, going beyond imagination.
世界に見せてあげる
I'll show the world.
アクセスしてみない？
Why don't you try accessing?
後悔なんて ここにない
Regrets aren't here.
それぞれ違った 心で
With each different heart,
作る輪
a circle we create.
ファンサ
Fansa
好きになって もっと
Love me more.
私を見て もっと
Look at me more.
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
Repayment is a love-filled blown kiss!
気のせいじゃない 目が合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting!
ハート作って
Make a heart!
恋しちゃってください！
Please fall in love with me!
やれること何でもします
I'll do anything I can
NG無しで体当たり挑戦
Taking on challenges head-on with no NGs
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Anti-comments I found while ego-searching
ふざけんな誰よりわかってるし
Don't mess with me, I know better than anyone
でも大丈夫　ここに立てばみんながいる
But it's okay, when I stand here, everyone is here
いくよ！
Here I go!
好きになって！もっと！
Love me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキッス”で
My way of giving back is with a "blown kiss full of love"
虜にする！もっと！　夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll make you fall for me! More! I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって
Enjoy yourself
“愛のこもったスペシャルナイト”
It's a "special night full of love"
ファンサしちゃうぞ（・ω＜）
I'm gonna give you fanservice (・ω<)
お手紙も書いてください！
Please write me letters too!
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and treasure them
スキャンダルまだ早いけど
A scandal is still too early
裏切りません！宣言しときます（｀・ω・´）
I won't betray you! I'm declaring it now (｀・ω・´)
嫉妬や嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment
ふざけんな実力で勝ってやる
Don't mess with me, I'll win with my own skills
だから辞めない負けず嫌い私はいる
So I won't quit, I'm a sore loser, I am here
いくよ！
Here I go!
こぶし上げて！もっと！　汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fists! More! Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもったスパビーム”で
My way of giving back is with an "ai-filled Suba-Beam"
大歓声！もっと！　まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
A huge cheer! More! Not yet! Right? More!
受け止めてね
Please accept it
“愛のこもったわがままソング”
A "selfish song full of love"
ファンサしちゃうぞ（・ω＜）
I'm gonna give you fanservice (・ω<)
はぁ…終わりが近づく　寂しいね
Haa... the end is near, it's lonely, isn't it?
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying
次も次もまた会えるよね？約束！
We'll meet again next time, and the time after that, right? It's a promise!
今日はみんなのおかげで最高の4周年になりました！
Thanks to everyone, today has become the best 4th anniversary!
本当に本当にありがとう！
Thank you so, so much!
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Words filled with kindness
心無い誰かの言葉さえも
And even the heartless words of someone
必要（なんだ）必要なんだ強くなろう
Are necessary, they're necessary, let's become stronger
好きに叫べ！もっと！　楽しんじゃえ！もっと！
Shout as much as you like! More! Just enjoy it! More!
忘れないで特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, may it become a special day
共に歌おうずっと！
Let's sing together forever!
共に歩もうずっと！
Let's walk together forever!
合言葉はとびっきりのＬＯＶＥ
The watchword is the very best L-O-V-E
好きになって！もっと！　私を見て！もっと！
Love me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキッス”で
My way of giving back is with a "blown kiss full of love"
虜にする！もっと！　夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll make you fall for me! More! I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって
Enjoy yourself
“愛のこもったスペシャルナイト”
It's a "special night full of love"
ファンサしちゃうぞ（・ω＜）
I'm gonna give you fanservice (・ω<)
はーい！というわけで、ファンサでしたー！
Alright! So, that was Fansa!
みんな、どうですか？この可愛い新衣装ー！
Everyone, how do you like this cute new costume!
可愛いでしょ！
It's cute, right!
ちょっと…はぁ…ちょっと待ってね。ふぅ、ふぅ、ふぅ…
Wait... ah... give me a second. *Panting*
スバルもね、テンション上がって全力で踊っちゃったからさ！
Subaru got so hyped up that I danced with all my might!
はい、というわけでですね、この最高な新衣装は
Alright, so this awesome new costume was
スバルの母ちゃん、しぐれうい母ちゃんに作ってもらいましたー！イェーイ！
made by Subaru's mother, Shigure Ui-mother! Yay!
どうどうどう？
How is it, how is it?
スカートも可愛いでしょ？
The skirt is cute too, right?
これね、スバルのおすすめポイントその1！この可愛いリボン！
This is Subaru's recommendation point number one! This cute ribbon!
そしてその2！みんなね、なんか見たことあるなーと思う人いるんじゃないでしょうか。
And number two! Everyone, I bet there are people who think they've seen this somewhere before.
そうなんです！この衣装ですね、新衣装のスバルの新衣装、
That's right! This costume, the new costume, Subaru's new costume is...
あのアイドル衣装のね、進化バージョンとなっておりまーす！
a powered-up version of that idol costume!
ということでね、このズボンなんかもうね、なんか見たことあるなーという…
And so, these shorts too, you might think you've seen them...
ちょっとお腹がね、ポンポンが丸...
My stomach is a bit, the tummy is round...
そう、というね、可愛らしい仕様になっております。
Yes, so it has a cute design like this.
あとここね、コサージュとかもね、可愛いでしょ！
And here, the corsage and all, it's cute, right?!
帽子もね、まんまるで可愛いんだよね。
The hat is also round and cute, isn't it?
めっちゃまんまる。
Super round.
これね、ひまわりも付けてもらいました。
This, I also had a sunflower put on it.
手袋も！うわああ！
Gloves too! Waaaah!
はい、ということで是非ね、たくさんスクショして、スクショして、スクショして、
Yes, so please take lots of screenshots, screenshots, screenshots,
えー是非ね、Twitterで呟いてください。みんなのおかげです、ありがとう！
and please tweet them on Twitter. It's all thanks to everyone, thank you!
はい、ということでですね、このあとも、なんとこの衣装はまだこれだけじゃない！
Yes, so, after this, this costume is not just this!
このあともですね、びっくりするような、いろんなことが起こるかもしれない。
After this, various surprising things might happen.
この衣装もなんと、これだけではない。この衣装が秘める可能性は無限大！
This costume, as it turns out, isn't just this. The potential this costume holds is infinite!
ということでなのでね、是非みんなもね、絶対に見逃すな！要チェックですよ！
So, everyone, definitely don't miss it! Keep a close eye!
はい、本当にね、このあとスバルもね、今ね、ドキドキするようなね、
Yes, really, after this Subaru will also... there will be exciting things,
びっくりすることがたくさん起こるので、是非チェックしてみてください。うん。
and many surprising things, so please check them out. Yeah.
さあそれではね、なんだ！もう次の曲の時間だ！そろそろ行かねばならん。
Now then, what! It's already time for the next song! I have to go soon.
それではですね、次の曲に行きたいと思います！レッツ・ゴー！準備してくるよ！
Well then, I'd like to go to the next song! Let's go! I'll go get ready!
フォニイ
作詞・作曲：ツミキ
Phony
Lyrics & Composition: Tsumiki
この世で毒より綺麗な花はないわ
In this world, no flower is more beautiful than poison
なぜならば全ては嘘でできている
Because everything is made of lies
アンチパシー
Antipathy
らるらりら
Larulalira
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair hits my umbrella
湿らす前髪と心 煩わしいわ
My damp bangs and heart are annoying
いつしか言の葉はとうに枯れきって
Before I knew it, words had already withered away
言の実が足元に熟れている
The fruit of words is ripening at my feet
鏡に映り嘘を描いて
Reflecting in the mirror, drawing lies
自らを見失ったパペット
A puppet that lost itself
パッパッパラッパッパラッパッパ
Pappappara...
なぞなぞ 数えて遊びましょう
Riddles, let's count and play
パッパッパラッパッパラッパッパ
Pappappara...
なぜなぜ ここで踊ってるのでしょう
Why, why am I dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't understand even simple things
あたしって何だっけ
What was I again?
それすら夜の目に綻ばされて
Even that is unraveled by the night's eyes
愛のように 消える 消える
Disappearing, disappearing like love
さよならも言えぬまま泣いた
I cried without even being able to say goodbye
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony phony phony
嘘に絡まっている あたしはフォニイ
I'm a phony, entangled in lies
アンチパシー
Antipathy
いつしか空の根が嫌になりあって
Before long, the roots of the sky grew to hate each other
色の眼があなたを説いている
The eyes of color are persuading you
鏡に映れ あたしを描いて
Reflect in the mirror, draw me
誰もが身間違ったパペット
A puppet that everyone mistook
どうして 愛なんてものに群がり
Why do we flock to things like love?
それを欲して生きるのだ
And live while wanting it?
今日も 泳いでいる夜の電車が
Today, too, the night train that is swimming...
通り過ぎていく
is passing by
踊り明かせ
Dance the night away
パッパッパラッパッパラッパッパ
Pappappara...
なぞなぞ 騙して歌いましょう
Riddles, let's deceive and sing
パッパッパラッパッパラッパッパ
Pappappara...
なぜなぜ ここが痛むのでしょう
Why, why does it hurt here?
惨憺な日々は変わらないわ
The wretched days don't change
絶望の雨は止まないわ
The rain of despair doesn't stop
さよならも言えぬまま泣いた
I cried without even being able to say goodbye
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony phony phony
嘘に絡まっている あたしは
I am entangled in lies...
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't understand even simple things
あたしって何だっけ
What was I again?
それすら夜の目に綻ばされて
Even that is unraveled by the night's eyes
愛のように 消える 消える
Disappearing, disappearing like love
さよなら またねと呟いた
I whispered "Goodbye, see you again"
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony phony phony
嘘に絡まっている あたしはフォニイ
I'm a phony, entangled in lies
造花だけが知っている 秘密のフォニイ
A secret phony that only artificial flowers know
時を刻む唄
作詞・作曲：麻枝准
Toki wo Kizamu Uta
Lyrics & Composition: Jun Maeda
時を刻む唄
作詞・作曲：麻枝准
Song that Carves Time
Lyrics/Composition: Jun Maeda
落ちていく砂時計ばかり見てるよ
I'm only looking at the hourglass as it falls
逆さまにすればほらまた始まるよ
If you turn it upside down, look, it'll start again
刻んだだけ進む時間に
In the time that advances as much as it's carved
いつか僕も入れるかな
I wonder if I can enter it someday too
君だけが過ぎ去った坂の途中は
The middle of the hill where only you passed by
温かな日だまりがいくつもできてた
There were many warm sunny spots
僕一人がここで優しい
I'm alone here, reflecting on...
暖かさを思い返してる
...that gentle warmth
君だけを 君だけを
Only you, only you
好きでいたよ
...did I love
風で目が 滲んで
My eyes are blurred by the wind
遠くなるよ
And you're getting further away
いつまでも覚えているよ
I'll remember forever
何一つ変わっても
Even if every single thing changes
一つだけ 一つだけ
Just one thing, just one thing
ありふれたものだけど
It's a common thing, but
見せてやる 輝きに満ちたもの
I'll show you something full of radiance
肌寒い日が続くもう春なのに
Chilly days continue, even though it's already spring
目覚まし時計より早く起きた朝
The morning I woke up earlier than the alarm clock
三人分の朝ご飯を作る君が
You, making breakfast for three people
そこに立っている
...are standing there
君だけが 君だけが
Only you, only you
そばにいないよ
...are not by my side
昨日まで すぐそばで
Until yesterday, right beside me
僕を見てたよ
...you were looking at me
君だけを 君だけを
Only you, only you
好きでいたよ
...did I love
君だけと 君だけと
Only with you, only with you
歌う 唄だよ
...is the song I sing
僕たちの 僕たちの
Our, our...
刻んだ時だよ
...carved time
片方だけ続くなんて
To think it would continue for only one side
僕は嫌だよ
I hate it
いくよ！
Here we go!
Q&A リサイタル！
作詞・作曲：田淵智也
Q&A Recital!
Lyrics/Composition: Tomoya Tabuchi
今日もこの胸は 張りつめたまま
Today as well, my heart remains tight
放課後に包まれて 君を見てる lady-ready?
Wrapped in the after-school atmosphere, I'm watching you. Lady-ready?
ずっと足並みは 揃わないまま
Our steps remain out of sync
続くから内緒だよ 少しつめて lady-ready?
It'll keep going, so it's a secret. Move a little closer. Lady-ready?
知りすぎて知らないから
I know too much, so I don't know
聞こえないふりが上手に なって
I've gotten good at pretending I can't hear
深呼吸ひとつしたら目を開けて
Take one deep breath and open your eyes
自問自答やめて 何気なく「おはよう」なんて言っちゃってる
Stop the self-questioning and find myself casually saying "Good morning"
ハイ! ハイ!
Hey! Hey!
呆れるくらい全部君が欲しいよ ハートは涙でいっぱい
I want all of you to an exasperating degree. My heart is full of tears.
恋のいろはとかまだ分かってないんだ
I still don't understand the basics of love
何度も繰り返すけど寸前でまた次回へ
I repeat it over and over, but right before the end, it's "to be continued"
スウィートな乙女心はあいにく取り扱ってないのです
Unfortunately, this sweet maidenly heart isn't something I handle.
ねぇ、これがアイ・ラブ・ユー
Hey, this is "I love you"
やっと手に入れた はずのパノラマ
The panorama I was supposed to have finally gotten
2歩進み2歩下がる なんでだっけ lady-ready?
Two steps forward, two steps back. Why was that? Lady-ready?
ゴールできなくちゃ 止まれないから
If I can't reach the goal, I can't stop
分からないままでもね いいよ だから lady-ready?
It's okay even if I don't understand, so... lady-ready?
昨日の答えなんてさ
Yesterday's answer...
今日の答えの前では ほらね
Is nothing before today's answer, see?
もう勝てそうもないくらい好きだから
Because I love you so much I can't possibly win anymore
知らないことはいつか知れたらいいなって言っちゃおうかな
Maybe I'll just say, "It'd be nice if I could find out the things I don't know someday"
ハイ! ハイ!
Hey! Hey!
取り留めないシーンでも大事だからね アンダーラインを引いて
Even random scenes are important, so draw an underline
恋の試験科目に加えておいてよ
Add them to the subjects of the love exam
時々に君の心に何百マイルのディスタンス?
Sometimes, how many hundreds of miles of distance are in your heart?
なんてね 気にしすぎかな だけどそれが本心なのです
Just kidding, am I worrying too much? But those are my true feelings.
こんなあんな時はどうしたらいいの?
What should I do in times like this or that?
慣れたメロディを口ずさむように
Like humming a familiar melody
君の中の私はどこにいるの?
Where am I inside of you?
ぐるぐる回って 四六時中リサイタル
Round and round, a recital 24/7
ス・バ・ル! ス・バ・ル! L・O・V・E ス・バ・ル!
SU-BA-RU! SU-BA-RU! L-O-V-E SU-BA-RU!
さて ありありありあ せんでぃっと
Well, Ari-ari-ari-a send it
Someday I really really send it precious for you!
さて ありありありあ せんでぃっと
Well, Ari-ari-ari-a send it
いつかその日が来たら 大切な声を聞いて
When that day finally comes, listen to my precious voice
恋に予約録画はありえないから 逃さないで
There's no such thing as scheduled recording for love, so don't miss it
呆れるくらい全部君が好きだよ ハートは笑顔でいっぱい
I love all of you to an exasperating degree. My heart is full of smiles.
恋のいろはも少し分かりたいんだ
I want to understand the basics of love a little more
何度も繰り返すけど寸前でまた次回へ
I repeat it over and over, but right before the end, it's "to be continued"
スウィートな乙女心は依然取り扱ってないのです
I'm still not handling this sweet maidenly heart.
ねぇ、これがアイ・ラブ・ユー
Hey, this is "I love you"
Precious for you!
さて ありありありあ せんでぃっと
Well, Ari-ari-ari-a send it
Precious for you!
さて ありありありあ せんでぃっと
Well, Ari-ari-ari-a send it
Precious for you!
さて ありありありあ せんでぃっと
Well, Ari-ari-ari-a send it
Precious for you!
さて ありありありあ せんでぃっと
Well, Ari-ari-ari-a send it
はい! ということで Q&Aリサイタルでした!
Yes! And that was Q&A Recital!
うわぁぁ!
Waaaa!
ちょっとね 本当にいっぱーい頑張ったから、ちょっと待って
Give me a sec, I really worked super hard, so just a moment
うー、ふー
Whew...
ふぅー
Phew...
うわー
Uwaa!
あつーい！
It's hot!
ちょっとお水飲んでくるね
I'm gonna go drink some water.
待ってて、うわー
Wait for me, uwaa!
うめー！
So good!
はい！ということでですね
Alright! So,
みんなライブを楽しんでくれているかな？
Is everyone enjoying the live?
うわあああー
Waaaa!
声がたくさん聞こえます！ということでですね
I can hear so many voices! So,
はっ、どうですか？この、全部パージしたですね
Ha, how is it? This fully-purged...
スバルの新衣装！
Subaru's new costume!
しぐれういかーちゃんがね、作ってくれました
Shigure Ui-kaachan made it for me.
かーちゃんありがとう！
Thanks, Kaachan!
後ろもですね、すっごく可愛いんですねこれ
The back is also really cute.
可愛い！
It's so cute!
お花がね、可愛いです
The flowers are cute.
おまんじゅうみたいな帽子もね、ひまわりも全部可愛いんですけど
The manju-like hat and sunflowers are all so cute.
ありがとうございました、しぐれういかーちゃんありがとね
Thank you so much, Shigure Ui-kaachan, thanks.
はい、ということで！それではですね
Alright! Now then,
ここでグッズ告知タイム！行きたいと思います！
It's time for the goods announcement!
まずは、こちら！ドン！
First, here's this! Bam!
大空スバル活動4周年記念グッズ！イエーイ！
Oozora Subaru 4th Anniversary Goods! Yay!
活動4周年記念 11月20日販売開始
4th Anniversary Commemoration - Sales start Nov 20
それでは、フルセットの内容を見ていきましょう、ドン！
Now, let's look at the full set contents, bam!
活動4周年記念フルセット
4th Anniversary Commemorative Full Set
おー、こちらですね！こちらがですね、フルセットの内容となっております
Oh, here it is! These are the contents of the full set.
それでは詳しく、ちょっとね見ていこうかな？まずはまずはドン！
Now let's take a closer look. First of all, bam!
おー！ポップアップアクリルスタンド！ということでですね
Oh! Pop-up acrylic stand!
ポップアップアクリルスタンド
Pop-up Acrylic Stand
これはしぐれういかーちゃん描き下ろしの、スバルの新衣装のですね、アクリルスタンドとなっております
This is an acrylic stand of Subaru's new costume drawn by Shigure Ui-kaachan.
ちょっとね、プラスチック好きだから作っちゃった、あははは
I like plastic, so I ended up making one, hahaha.
はい、でこれ立体なのでね、ぜひねお部屋に飾ってください
Yes, it's 3D, so please display it in your room.
お願いします、わー！
Please, waaa!
それでは続いて、こちらドン！
Next up, this, bam!
えー、アクリルバッジです！
Uh, acrylic badges!
アクリルバッジ (2個入り)
Acrylic Badges (Set of 2)
これはですね、ぜひとも学校に、職場に、そしてライブにですね、一緒にねカバンにつけて、連れてってください
Please take them with you to school, work, and lives by attaching them to your bag.
加川先生の描き下ろしとなっております。このね、スバあじ、スバあじ...
Drawn by Kagawa-sensei. This Subaru duck, Subaru duck...
このスバルダックすごいね、なんかあの可愛いんです。お揃いの帽子を被っています
This Subaru duck is so cute. It's wearing a matching hat.
サムネイルのスバルもいるのでね、ぜひ記念にチェックしてみてください
The Subaru from the thumbnail is also there, so please check it out for the anniversary.
それじゃ次はこれだ！ドン！
Next is this! Bam!
ショルダーバッグ！
Shoulder bag!
ショルダーバッグ
Shoulder Bag
これはですね、あの、ショルダーバッグはペンライトですね、ペンライトがですね、おー
This shoulder bag fits penlights, oh.
入るぐらいのですね、大きさとなって、いるらしい。結構ね、ボリュームがね、あるそうです
It seems to be big enough to fit them. It apparently has a lot of volume.
なのでですね、ぜひねライブなどに、ライブなどに行く時にですね、ぜひ連れてってください。これも一緒にお願いします
So please take it with you to lives and such. This too, please.
はい、そしてですね、全部フルセットの特典はこちら、ドン！
Yes, and here's the bonus for the full set, bam!
フルセット購入特典 大空スバルからの複製手書きお手紙
Full Set Bonus - Duplicate Handwritten Letter from Oozora Subaru
ちょっとお手紙をね、書きました
I wrote a little letter.
ちょっと恥ずかしいんですけど、まあね、ぜひね、ぜひね、チェックしてみてください
It's a bit embarrassing, but please check it out.
ちょっとねあんまり普段書かないんですけど、書いてみました
I don't usually write them, but I tried writing one.
よかったらですね、ぜひフルセットを買って、スバルからのお手紙読んでくださいということで
If you'd like, please buy the full set and read the letter from Subaru.
これがですね、グッズの告知になりました！
So that was the goods announcement!
はい、そしてですね！なんと！
Yes, and! Can you believe it!
このあと、まだライブは続くよな！
The live continues after this!
続きます！もう終盤なんですけれども
It continues! Even though we're nearing the end.
えー、もう終盤なのか、あっという間ですね。でもまだまだライブは続くので
Huh, it's already the end? That was fast. But the live is still going.
それでは次はね、なんと！
So next, can you believe it!
新曲が、あるとか！
There might be... a new song!
ないとか、ちょっとね。はい、ということで
Or not, maybe. Yes, so...
それではですね、せっかくなので、センターステージへワープしたいと思います！
So, since we're here, I want to warp to the center stage!
それでは行くぞ！せーの、ワープ！
Here we go! One, two, warp!
はい、ということで！早速行きたいと思います！
Yes! Let's get right into it!
それでは新曲です、聴いてください
Now, here's my new song. Please listen.
スターライト！
Starlight!
スターライト 作詞・作曲・編曲：DIVELA
Starlight - Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: DIVELA
描いた未知のキャンバス重ねる景色
The landscape layering on the unknown canvas I painted
繋いでみて繰り返していく衝動
Trying to connect, the repeating impulse
揺らいだ目の前に広がる世界
The world spreading out before my wavering eyes
星屑のメロディ歌に乗せた
I put the stardust melody into a song
クラッと鮮やかに眩ませるように
Dazzlingly and vividly, as if to blind
駆け抜けるよスターライト
I'll run through, Starlight
We can fly
そう僕らは いつしか 夢の中 引かれて
So before we knew it, we were drawn into a dream,
ただがむしゃらに 走り続けたよ
and just kept running recklessly.
無限の宇宙に 響いた
The voice that echoed through the infinite universe
君を照らす声は
to shine on you,
どこへだって きらり 飛んでいけるんだ
it can fly sparkly anywhere.
愉快な仲間と歩いた非日常
An extraordinary life I walked with my cheerful friends.
掴んでみて指先の 一等星
Try to grab the first-magnitude star at your fingertips.
滲んでゆく目の前に広がった限界は
The limits that spread out before my eyes and began to blur,
皆の手重ねてぶっ壊して
were smashed by all of our hands overlapping.
吸い込まれそうな夜空を見上げて
Looking up at the night sky that seems to suck me in,
今叫ぶよ スターライト
I'll shout it now: Starlight!
I wanna be
そう僕らは いつでも 側で笑い合って
so we'll always laugh together by each other's side,
あふれる声が 遠くこだまする
our overflowing voices echoing far away.
願いのかけらを灯した 君の腕を引いて
Pulling your arm as you light up the fragments of your wishes,
どこへだって きらり 飛んでいけるんだ
we can fly sparkly anywhere.
ちょこっと不安な日も 魔法をかけてハッピー
Even on slightly uneasy days, cast a spell and be happy.
百人力で乗り越えていこう
Let's overcome it with the strength of a hundred people.
アクアブルーに染まる 大空にめがけた
Aiming for the vast sky dyed in aqua blue,
鼓動が弾んでく
my heart is pounding.
We can fly
そう僕らは この日を ずっと待ってたんだ
so we've been waiting for this day for a long time.
まだ覚めないで
Please don't wake up yet.
Starlight
僕らは 止まらない その光が消える
We won't stop until that light fades out,
一秒前まで 走り続けるよ
we'll keep running until the second before then.
無限の宇宙に 響いた 君を照らす声を
The voice that echoed through the infinite universe to shine on you,
強く抱いて きらり 輝いてゆけ
hold it tight and go on shining sparkly.
次は、最後の曲になります。
The next song will be the last one.
この4年間スバルは、みんなとここまで歩いてこれて、とっても幸せでした！
Subaru was very happy to have been able to walk this far with everyone over the past four years!
これからもずっと歩いていこうと思うので、応援よろしくお願いします！
I'm planning to keep walking forever, so please continue to support me!
それでは聴いてください。最後の曲は、アカシア。
Now, please listen. The last song is 'Acacia'.
透明よりも綺麗な あの輝きを 確かめに行こう
Let's go and see that radiance, even clearer than transparency.
そうやって始まったんだよ たまに忘れるほど強い理由
That's how it started. A reason so strong I sometimes forget it.
冷たい雨に濡れる時は 足音比べ 騒ぎながら行こう
When we get wet in the cold rain, let's compare our footsteps and make some noise as we go.
太陽の代わりに唄を 君と僕と世界の声で
Let's have a song instead of the sun, with your voice, mine, and the voice of the world.
いつか君を見つけた時に 君に僕も見つけてもらったんだな
When I found you one day, you found me too, didn't you?
今 目が合えば笑うだけさ 言葉の外側で
Now, if our eyes meet, we'll just laugh, beyond words.
ゴールはきっとまだだけど もう死ぬまでいたい場所にいる
The goal is surely still ahead, but I'm already in the place where I want to stay until I die.
隣で 君の側で 魂がここだよって叫ぶ
Beside you, by your side, my soul shouts that it's here.
泣いたり笑ったりする時 君の命が揺れる時
When we cry or laugh, when your life flickers,
誰より近くで 特等席で 僕も同じように 息をしていたい
closer than anyone else, in a special seat, I want to be breathing just like you.
君の一歩は僕より遠い 間違いなく君の凄いところ
Your step is further than mine, that's definitely a great thing about you.
足跡は僕の方が多い 間違いなく僕の凄いところ
I have more footprints, that's definitely a great thing about me.
真っ暗闇が怖い時は 怖
When I'm afraid of the pitch-black darkness, I'm a-
...を比べ ふざけながらいこう
...comparing them, let's go while joking around.
太陽が沢山あっても歩ける
Even if there are many suns, I can walk.
君と照らす世界が見える
I can see the world illuminated with you.
言えないこと聞かないままで
Without saying anything, without hearing anything,
消えない傷の意味知らないままで
Without knowing the meaning of the wounds that won't fade,
でも目が合えば笑えるのさ
But if our eyes meet, we can laugh.
涙を挟んでも
Even if tears come between us.
転んだら手を貸してもらうよりも
Rather than having you lend a hand when I fall,
優しい言葉選んでもらうよりも
Rather than having you choose kind words for me,
隣で 隣で 信じてほしいんだ
Beside me, beside me, I want you to believe in me.
どこまでも一緒に行けると
That we can go together anywhere.
ついに辿り着くその時
When we finally arrive,
夢の正体に触れる時
When we touch the true nature of our dreams,
必ず近くで一番そばで
Always nearby, right by your side,
君の目に映る景色にいたい
I want to be in the scenery reflected in your eyes.
あの輝きを
That radiance,
君に会えたから見えた
I saw it because I met you.
あの輝きを確かめに
To confirm that radiance,
いこう Oh yeah yeah yeah yeah
let's go. Oh yeah yeah yeah yeah
どんな最後が待っていようと
No matter what end awaits,
もう離さない手を繋いだよ
I won't let go anymore, I've held your hand.
隣で 隣で 君のそばで
Beside you, beside you, right by your side,
魂がここだよと叫ぶさ
My soul will shout, "I'm right here!"
そして理由なき光る時
And when we shine for no reason,
僕らを理由が抱きしめる時
When a reason embraces us,
誰より近くで とびきりで
Closer than anyone, exceptionally,
僕の見たい君を君に伝えたい
I want to tell you about the "you" I want to see.
君がいることを君に伝えたい
I want to tell you that you are here.
そうやって始まったんだよ
That's how it started.
Oh yeah yeah yeah yeah
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
4周年ありがとう！ 君の笑顔が沢山（来年も）見れますように。
Thanks for the 4th anniversary! May next year bring many more smiles from you!!
A new legend begins
Draw your Sword
SAUSAGE LEGEND 2 SUBARU & KOYORI
Don't miss it !